{
  "topics": [
    "All topics",
    "Computer Architecture - Part 1",
    "Computer Architecture - Part 2",
    "Computer Architecture - Part 3",
    "Computer Architecture - Part 4",
    "Numbering Systems - Part 1",
    "Numbering Systems - Part 2",
    "Programming Basics",
    "Object, Types and Values",
    "Character Encoding",
    "Computation - Part 1",
    "Computation - Part 2",
    "Databases - Part 1",
    "Databases - Part 2",
    "Databases - Part 3",
    "Databases - Part 4",
    "Computer Networks - Part 1",
    "Computer Networks - Part 2",
    "Computer Networks - Part 3",
    "Flowcharts and Pseudocode",
    "Logic and Truth Tables"
  ],
  "cards": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "What are the steps involved in the functioning of a computer?",
      "answer": "Accepts digitized input, processes it according to a list or instructions (Program), and produces the resulting output.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "What are the five functional main units of a computer",
      "answer": "input, output, arithmetic and logic, control and memory",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "How do the 5 functional units of a computer relate to the steps of computer functionality?",
      "answer": "Input and output: I/O; arithmetic and logic, control: processor; memory: stores the program and data",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "What is the input unit of a computer responsible for?",
      "answer": "accepting a digitized input and converting it into a corresponding binary code",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "What is the memory unit of a computer responsible for?",
      "answer": "storage of programs and data",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "What are the two types of storage?",
      "answer": "Primary and secondary",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "What is primary storage used for?",
      "answer": "Storing fast memory that operates at electronic speeds; contains large number of semiconductor storage cells that are able to store one bit of information each",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "What is secondary storage used for?",
      "answer": "Storing large amounts of programs and data that are accessed infrequently (e.g. magnetic disks, CDROMs)",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "What is the ALU (Arithmetic and Logic Unit)?",
      "answer": "executes most computer operations; operands are transferred to the processor and operations are performed by the ALU; operands are stored in the processor in high-speed storage elements called registers",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "What is the Control Unit?",
      "answer": "A defined, physically separated unit that coordinates operations of the other units of a computer; sends control signals to other units and registers their states",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "What is the Output unit?",
      "answer": "counterpart of input unit that sends processed results to external parts (e.g. printer or monitor)",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "What is data?",
      "answer": "information such as alphabets, number, symbols, images, etc. in raw and unorganized form",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "How is data represented in computers?",
      "answer": "in binary number format (e.g. 1) or binary code format (e.g. 0001)",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "what data format is used at all stages of processing within a computer?",
      "answer": "binary code format",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "What is ASCII?",
      "answer": "the American Standard Code for Information Interchange; text code standard for conversion of numbers, letters and symbols into binary code; letters and symbols are converted into decimal equivalents and then converted to binary code format.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "What is computer memory?",
      "answer": "computer hardware with integrated circuits used to store information; programs and data are usually stored in memory and accessed during processing",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "What are the two types of computer memory?",
      "answer": "Volatile (temporary -- RAM) and non-volatile memory (persistent -- ROM, flash memory, HDD, SDD)",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "What is volatile memory?",
      "answer": "Computer memory requiring power to maintain stored information; it is primary storage in computers and an example is RAM (Random Access Memory).",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "What is non-volatile memory?",
      "answer": "Computer memory that can maintain stored information even when the power is interrupted / off.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "What are the two categories of non-volatile memory?",
      "answer": "Electrically addressed systems--ROM (Read Only Memory and flash memory); Mechanically addressed systems--hard disks, magnetic tape.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "What is RAM also known as?",
      "answer": "Read and Write Memory.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "What are the two types of RAM?",
      "answer": "Static and Dynamic.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "What is Static RAM?",
      "answer": "Random access memory that uses flip-flop to store each bit of data; typically used in CPU cache.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "What is Dynamic RAM?",
      "answer": "Random access memory that uses capacitors within an integrated circuit to store each bit of data; typically used in computer’s main memory.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "What are the three classifications of ROM?",
      "answer": "PROM, EPROM and EEPROM",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "What is PROM?",
      "answer": "Programmable Read Only Memory. Type of ROM that is programmed via PROM programmer and can only be programmed once.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "What is EPROM?",
      "answer": "Erasable Programmable Read Only Memory. Type of ROM where data can be erased with UV light and reprogrammed. Can only endure 1000 erasing / reprogramming cycles.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "What is EEPROM?",
      "answer": "Electrically Erasable Programmable Read Only Memory. Type of ROM with similar semiconductor structure to EPROM and can be electrically erased and reprogrammed.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "What is Flash Memory?",
      "answer": "An Electronically non-volatile memory that can be electrically erased and reprogrammed--modern version of EEPROM with faster erasure / rewrites; USB drives and SSDs (Solid State Drives) are a category of flash memory.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 31,
      "question": "What is Cache Memory?",
      "answer": "Type of memory used to speed up and synchronize with CPU and acts as buffer between RAM and CPU. It holds frequently requested data and instructions from the main memory so that it is immediately available to the CPU.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 32,
      "question": "What is a Cache Hit and Cache Miss?",
      "answer": "When a processor wants to read a location in main memory it first checks for a corresponding entry in cache memory. When the processor finds the memory location in cache, it is a Cache Hit; when the processor does not find one, it is a Cache Miss--where the cache allocates a new entry and copies data from main memory.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 33,
      "question": "What is the Hit Ratio?",
      "answer": "Ratio used to measure the performance of cache memory. Number of cache hits / total accesses",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 34,
      "question": "What are the two approaches to writing to cache memory?",
      "answer": "Write-through approach--write operation is done synchronously to both cache and main memory; Write-back approach--write operation is done only to cache and write to main memory is postponed until modified content is to be replaced by another cache block.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 35,
      "question": "What are the two approaches to write miss (cache miss during write operation)?",
      "answer": "Write allocate--cache memory makes room for the data in a write miss and loads data; No-write allocate--data is not loaded into cache in write miss and is written into main memory.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 36,
      "question": "What are the two units of the CPU (Central Processing Unit)?",
      "answer": "Arithmetic and Logic Unit; Control Unit.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 37,
      "question": "How is the ALU (Arithmetic and Logic Unit) designed to operate in the CPU?",
      "answer": "Designed to be powerful enough to handle some complex operations, but not so powerful that when it performs a more complex operation that it consumes more energy and dissipates heat.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 114,
      "question": "What are numbers?",
      "answer": "Mathematical objects used to count, label or measure.",
      "topic": "Numbering Systems - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 115,
      "question": "What are numerals?",
      "answer": "Symbols used to represent numbers.",
      "topic": "Numbering Systems - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 116,
      "question": "What is the most commonly used numeral system?",
      "answer": "The Arabic positional decimal system.",
      "topic": "Numbering Systems - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 117,
      "question": "What is Positional Representation?",
      "answer": "System where the value of a digit depends on the position within a number; allows for numbers to be broken up into component parts.",
      "topic": "Numbering Systems - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 118,
      "question": "What are Nibbles?",
      "answer": "Groups of four digits in binary representation.",
      "topic": "Numbering Systems - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 119,
      "question": "What are Bytes?",
      "answer": "Groups of eight digits in binary representation.",
      "topic": "Numbering Systems - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 120,
      "question": "What are Nibbles?",
      "answer": "Groups of four digits in binary representation.",
      "topic": "Programming Basics"
    },
    {
      "id": 121,
      "question": "What are Bytes?",
      "answer": "Groups of eight digits in binary representation.",
      "topic": "Programming Basics"
    },
    {
      "id": 122,
      "question": "What are Objects?",
      "answer": "Regions of memory with corresponding Types.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 123,
      "question": "What are Types?",
      "answer": "Specify what kinds of data can be placed into Objects.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 124,
      "question": "What is a Variable?",
      "answer": "A named Object.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 125,
      "question": "What are Values?",
      "answer": "Data items placed into Objects.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 126,
      "question": "What are Definitions?",
      "answer": "Statements that create a Variable by introducing and allocating memory for it within a program.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 127,
      "question": "What is Initialization?",
      "answer": "Practice of setting an initial value for a Variable--considered a good practice.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 128,
      "question": "What is an assignment operator?",
      "answer": "An equals sign that changes the value of an variable.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 129,
      "question": "What is an Immutable Data Type?",
      "answer": "A data type that when its value is changed results in a newly allocated object.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 130,
      "question": "What is Garbage Collection?",
      "answer": "Reclamation of memory occupied by Objects that are no longer used / needed.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 131,
      "question": "What are the four basic Data Types in Python?",
      "answer": "They are int, float, str and bool.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 132,
      "question": "How is the Data Type of an Object identified in Python?",
      "answer": "With the type() function.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 133,
      "question": "What are the four basic Data Type conversion functions in Python?",
      "answer": "They are int(), float(), str() and bool().",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 134,
      "question": "What are the Arithmetic Operators offered by Python?",
      "answer": "-\tSubtraction\n**\tExponentiation\n*\tMultiplication\n/\tDivision\n//\tInteger Division (divides and returns only quotient)\n%\tModulus (divided and returns only remainder)\n+\tAddition",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 135,
      "question": "What is the input() function in Python?",
      "answer": "A function that returns user input from a prompt--must be assigned to a Variable to capture input.",
      "topic": "Object, Types and Values"
    },
    {
      "id": 136,
      "question": "What is an Encoding Scheme?",
      "answer": "A representation bits into letters and symbols.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 137,
      "question": "How are decimal integers encoded to binary?",
      "answer": "By converting them from the base ten(decimal system) to the base two (binary system)",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 138,
      "question": "What is the function of ASCII?",
      "answer": "A table of characters, or character set, with corresponding bytes for each character.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 139,
      "question": "How is ASCII designed in regards to bits?",
      "answer": "ASCII was designed to represent all major characters in the English language use only 7 bits. Since computers use 8 bytes, it was possible to store an additional 128 characters in a single byte.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 140,
      "question": "How are the extended characters of ASCII used?",
      "answer": "Math symbols, accented characters, line-drawing characters and other symbols.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 141,
      "question": "What is the international standard for character encoding?",
      "answer": "ANSI (American National Standards Institute); same original 128 characters, but with different sets of extended characters to represent characters in other languages.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 142,
      "question": "What is Unicode?",
      "answer": "Form of character encoding where each letter maps to a code point--a symbolic representation of a character.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 164,
      "question": "What is UTF-8?",
      "answer": "Method of encoding Unicode code points with only the required amount of bytes; code points 0 - 127 is stored as a single byte, while 128+ are stored using more than one byte.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 165,
      "question": "What is a benefit of of using UTF-8?",
      "answer": "Text using only the first 128 characters in the ASCII characters is also valid UTF-8--no file conversion is necessary.",
      "topic": "Character Encoding"
    },
    {
      "id": 166,
      "question": "What is Computation?",
      "answer": "Accepting some type of input and producing some output.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 167,
      "question": "How should programmers express their computations?",
      "answer": "Correctly, simple and efficiently.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 168,
      "question": "What is abstraction?",
      "answer": "Hiding implementation details behind a convenient and general interface.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 169,
      "question": "What are Control Statements?",
      "answer": "Statements that are used to alter the order of evaluation.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 170,
      "question": "What are Selection Statements?",
      "answer": "Statement that allow the computer to make choices.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 171,
      "question": "What are Iteration Statements?",
      "answer": "Statements that allow the computer to execute a set of statements a definite number of times.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 172,
      "question": "How are conditions represented in an If Statement?",
      "answer": "if, elif and else",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 173,
      "question": "What did the first real program created by David Wheeler in 1949 do?",
      "answer": "It iterated through numbers and output squared exponents of each.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 174,
      "question": "What are the two main types of loops in Python?",
      "answer": "While and for loops.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 175,
      "question": "What is simple representation of a while loop that ends at 100?",
      "answer": "while (i < 100):",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 176,
      "question": "What is simple representation of a for loop that ends at 100?",
      "answer": "for i in range (0, 100, 1):",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 38,
      "question": "What type of operations are performed in the ALU (Arithmetic and Logic Unit)?",
      "answer": "Bit mathematical operations; each digit is a bit",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 39,
      "question": "What is used in substitution for for bit multiplication and division when the operations become too expensive in the ALU (Arithmetic and Logic Unit)?",
      "answer": "Addition for multiplication and subtraction for division.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 40,
      "question": "What are the 6 conditions the ALU can test for?",
      "answer": "Equal to, less than, greater than, less than or equal to, greater than or equal to, not equal",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 41,
      "question": "What is the Control Unit responsible for?",
      "answer": "Directs the operation of the processor and directs the flow of data between the CPU and other devices; directs the computer’s memory, ALU, and I/O how to respond to instructions that have been sent to the processor.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 42,
      "question": "What types of devices require a Control Unit?",
      "answer": "Control Processing Units (CPUs) and Graphics Processing Units (GPUs)",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 43,
      "question": "What are the main functions of the Control Unit?",
      "answer": "Coordination of sequence data in, out and between processors sub units; conversion of external instructions into sequence of control signals; fetches, decodes, handles execution and stores results.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 44,
      "question": "What are the two types of control units?",
      "answer": "Hardwired control unit; micro programmable control unit",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 45,
      "question": "What is a Hardwired Control Unit?",
      "answer": "Control unit with signals are generated by specially designed hardware logical circuits; modification of control signal generation method requires wiring changes of logical circuits",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 46,
      "question": "What is a Micro Programmable Control Unit?",
      "answer": "Control unit with signals generated by a control store containing encoded signals--does not generate signals from hardware circuits.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 47,
      "question": "How does the process flow of the CPU (Central Processing Unit) interact with Memory?",
      "answer": "The Control Unit interacts with the ALU (Arithmetic and Logic Unit); the ALU interacts with the Memory; the Memory interacts with the Control Unit.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 48,
      "question": "What are the 4 steps of processing operations of the CPU (Central Processing Unit)?",
      "answer": "Fetch--control unit fetches instruction from memory; Decode--control unit decodes instruction and sends control signals for data to be moved from memory to ALU; Execute--ALU unit executes arithmetic or logical instruction; Store--ALU stores result of operation in memory.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 49,
      "question": "What are the operands of the Machine Cycle",
      "answer": "I-time (instruction time--fetch and decode steps) + E-time (execution time--execute and store steps) = Machine Cycle",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 50,
      "question": "In computer terminology, what is a Bus?",
      "answer": "A communication system that acts as a connection between two or more devices.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 51,
      "question": "What are the 3 types of Buses?",
      "answer": "Address Bus; Data Bus; Control Bus.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 52,
      "question": "What is an Address Bus?",
      "answer": "Type of bus with conducting wires that carries address only and with unidirectional data flow.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 53,
      "question": "What is a Data Bus?",
      "answer": "Type of bus with conducting wires that carries data only and with bidirectional data flow.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 54,
      "question": "What is a Control Bus?",
      "answer": "Type of bus with conducting wires used to generate timing and control signals for all associated hardware.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 55,
      "question": "What are 5 Control Signals?",
      "answer": "Memory read, memory write; I/O read; I/O write; Opcode fetch",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 56,
      "question": "What are the flow steps of the integration of units in a computer?",
      "answer": "- Input device sends data\n- Data and program stored in memory\n- Accessing data and program from memory by CPU\n- Processing of data by CPU\n- Output or Secondary Storage?\nOutput → Sends data to output device\nSecondary Storage → Stores data and program in secondary storage",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 57,
      "question": "What are the main responsibilities of a microprocessor?",
      "answer": "Management of a computer’s arithmetic, logical and control activities.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 58,
      "question": "What are Machine Language Instructions?",
      "answer": "A microprocessor’s set of instructions--a string of 1s and 0s--for handling various operations.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 59,
      "question": "What are the 3 major number systems in computer science?",
      "answer": "Binary Number, Hexadecimal and Binary Arithmetic.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 60,
      "question": "What is the value of a binary number based on?",
      "answer": "The presence of 1 bits and their positional value.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 61,
      "question": "What is the hexadecimal system?",
      "answer": "Number system that uses base 16 with digits range from 0 - 15; 10 -15 is represented by the letters A - F.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 62,
      "question": "What are the three steps of the execution cycle?",
      "answer": "Fetching the Instruction from memory.\nIdentifying the instruction.\nExecuting the instruction.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 63,
      "question": "What are the two kinds of data addresses?",
      "answer": "Absolute address: direct reference of location\nSegment address: starting address of memory segment with the offset value",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 64,
      "question": "What are the three sections of an assembly program?",
      "answer": "Data, Bss, Text, and Comments",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 65,
      "question": "What is the Data section of an assembly program?",
      "answer": "Section used for declaring initialized data and constants that do not change at runtime.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 66,
      "question": "What is the Bss section of an assembly program?",
      "answer": "Section used for declaring variables.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 67,
      "question": "What is the Text section of an assembly program?",
      "answer": "Section used for keeping actual code and must begin with declaration “global _start”.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 68,
      "question": "How are Comments declared in an assembly program?",
      "answer": "They must begin with a semicolon and can contain any printable character including blank.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 69,
      "question": "What are registers in assembly code?",
      "answer": "The only place where math can be performed and frequently hold pointers referencing memory.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 70,
      "question": "What is the Segmented Memory Model?",
      "answer": "A model dividing system memory into independent segments referenced by pointers located in segment registers; each segment contains a specific type of data.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 71,
      "question": "What are the types of Memory Segments?",
      "answer": "Data Segment: represented by the .data and .bss sections and is used to declare the static, memory region,\nCode Segment: represented by the .text section and defines the area in memory that stores instruction codes.\nStack: stores values of data passed in the program and functions.",
      "topic": "Computer Architecture - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 72,
      "question": "What is a database?",
      "answer": "A representation of a set of relationships populated by data fitting within the relationship definition.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 73,
      "question": "What are Tuples in databases?",
      "answer": "The rows of data within a database table.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 74,
      "question": "What are attributes in databases?",
      "answer": "The columns within a database table; they describe the behavior of a table and how it interacts with other tables.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 75,
      "question": "What is the SELECT command in MySQL?",
      "answer": "It selects a particular set of tuples / rows from tables.\nExample: SELECT * FROM Table1;",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 76,
      "question": "What is the INSERT command in MySQL?",
      "answer": "It adds a new tuple to an existing database.\nExample: INSERT INTO Table1(name, age, dob) VALUES (‘name’, 18, ‘03/23/96’);",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 77,
      "question": "What is the DELETE command in MySQL?",
      "answer": "It removes a tuple from an existing database.\nExample: DELETE FROM Table1 WHERE name=’name’;",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 78,
      "question": "What is the UPDATE command in MySQL?",
      "answer": "It updates information in a tuple from an existing database.\nExample: UPDATE Table1 SET name=’name1’ WHERE id=’5’;",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 79,
      "question": "What are Entities in the context of databases?",
      "answer": "Abstractions of how data is stored; can be identities of tables created by compiling multiple attributes.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 80,
      "question": "How are Relations created in databases?",
      "answer": "They are made by the underlying logic of entity connections based on their attributes.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 81,
      "question": "What is the ER Model?",
      "answer": "The Entity-Relationship model is the visual representation of a database; composed of all basic elements of a database.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 82,
      "question": "What are Attributes within the ER Model?",
      "answer": "The building blocks of an entity that define how an entity works and its behavior.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 83,
      "question": "How are attributes used in a database table?",
      "answer": "They are used to identify a tuple as unique from all others in a table.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 84,
      "question": "What is a Candidate Key?",
      "answer": "Single or multiple attributes mandating the uniqueness of a tuple.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 85,
      "question": "What is a Composite Key?",
      "answer": "Multiple attributes in a tuple ensuring its uniqueness.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 86,
      "question": "What is a Primary Key?",
      "answer": "The main candidate key that is prioritized for making a tuple unique.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 87,
      "question": "What is a Foreign Key?",
      "answer": "Attribute that is a candidate key to another table connecting tables.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 88,
      "question": "What are the four major types of Attributes in database tables?",
      "answer": "Simple, Composite, Multivalued and Derived Attributes.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 89,
      "question": "What are Simple Attributes in database tables?",
      "answer": "Single value attributes that cannot be further divided into additional attributes.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 90,
      "question": "What are Composite Attributes in database tables?",
      "answer": "Attributes composed of two or more attributes.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 91,
      "question": "What are Multivalued Attributes in database tables?",
      "answer": "Attributes consisting of one or more values; values do not change and are static among all data fields.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 92,
      "question": "What are Derived Attributes in database tables?",
      "answer": "Attributes that are calculated from other attributes in the table.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 93,
      "question": "What are Entities in databases?",
      "answer": "Objects in both physical and conceptual existence.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 94,
      "question": "What are the two types of Entities in databases?",
      "answer": "Independent and Dependent Entities.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 95,
      "question": "What are Independent Entities within databases?",
      "answer": "Backbones of database functionality and behavior.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 96,
      "question": "What are Derived Entities within databases?",
      "answer": "Derived from independent entities to extend database behavior.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 97,
      "question": "What are Relationships in database tables?",
      "answer": "Interconnections in databases tables that allow for efficient operation and behaviors in certain tables.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 98,
      "question": "What are the three major types of Relationships in databases?",
      "answer": "One-to-many, one-to-one and many-to-many Relationships.,",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 99,
      "question": "What are One-to-Many Relationships in databases?",
      "answer": "A relationship where one entity maps to many unique ones.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 100,
      "question": "What are One-to-One Relationships in databases?",
      "answer": "A relationship where one entity maps to only one other entity.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 101,
      "question": "What are Many-to-Many Relationships in databases?",
      "answer": "A relationship where one entity maps to multiple others and vice-versa.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 102,
      "question": "What are the five basic commands within a database?",
      "answer": "SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE, and CREATE Commands.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 103,
      "question": "What are the Basic Guidelines of database commands?",
      "answer": "New lines for each command to denote different instructions for database processing and execution.\nQueries with multiple commands should be indented accordingly for readability and clarity.\nUppercase words must be commands or keywords.\nLowercase words must be used for user-defined attributes.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 104,
      "question": "What are the components of a SELECT command?",
      "answer": "SELECT DISTINCT item(s)\nFROM table(s)\nWHERE predicate\nGROUP BY field(s)\nORDER BY fields",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 105,
      "question": "What will the following query result in?\nSELECT name age FROM people",
      "answer": "The missing comma between age and name will return the name column from the people table with a column heading called age.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 106,
      "question": "What is one use of the UPDATE command?",
      "answer": "It can fix erroneous INSERT commands; it updates pre-existing data into correct data.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 107,
      "question": "What is the WHERE command?",
      "answer": "Used to specify a condition while fetching data from a single table or joining multiple tables.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 108,
      "question": "What is one limitation of the DELETE command?",
      "answer": "Only one table can be altered with the command at a time.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 109,
      "question": "What is the CREATE command?",
      "answer": "It creates tables to perform actions on and store data in; a table's primary key can be declared in this statement.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 110,
      "question": "What is the general structure of a CREATE TABLE statement?",
      "answer": "CREATE TABLE table1(attribute1, attribute2)",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 111,
      "question": "What are the typical data types used to declare attributes within a table?",
      "answer": "VARCHAR, INT and DATE",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 112,
      "question": "What are the miscellaneous commands?",
      "answer": "AVG, COUNT, COUNT(*), MAX, MIN, SUM",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 113,
      "question": "What is the AVG command?",
      "answer": "Takes a sum of specified attributes and divides them by the number of those same attributes.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 143,
      "question": "What is the COUNT command?",
      "answer": "Counts how many entries of a particular attribute exist in a table.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 144,
      "question": "What is the COUNT(*) command?",
      "answer": "Counts number of rows in a table irrespective of data within each attribute.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 145,
      "question": "What is the MAX command?",
      "answer": "Selects the attribute with the maximum value from the rows in a table.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 146,
      "question": "What is the MIN command?",
      "answer": "Selects the attribute with the minimum value from the rows in a table.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 147,
      "question": "What is the SUM command?",
      "answer": "Returns the summation of a specific attribute; only works with numerical data types.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 148,
      "question": "What is NoSQL?",
      "answer": "A non-relational database management system that does not require schemas to build.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 149,
      "question": "What are the five types of NoSQL databases?",
      "answer": "Key Value, Document-Based, Column-Based and Graph-Based.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 150,
      "question": "What is a Key Value NoSQL database?",
      "answer": "NoSQL database where data is stored in key-value pairs; related to a hash table where each key is unique and data can be accessed via a key.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 151,
      "question": "What is a Document-Based NoSQL database?",
      "answer": "NoSQL database similar to key-value system where keys are complete documents of information; definition attributes are flexible to user requirements.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 152,
      "question": "What is a Column-Based NoSQL database?",
      "answer": "NoSQL database where all columns are treated separately and are widely used to manage data warehouses; perform well with aggregation queries such as SUM, COUNT and AVG.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 153,
      "question": "What is a Graph-Based NoSQL database?",
      "answer": "NoSQL, multi-relational database where the relationships of entities are also stored; predominantly used in social networking databases.",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 154,
      "question": "What are some advantages of NoSQL databases?",
      "answer": "Can serve as primary data source for online apps\nOffer flexible scheme design\nDo not need dedicated, high-performance servers\nThere is no single point of failure in architecture\nPrimarily used OOP which is intuitive",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 155,
      "question": "What are some disadvantages of NoSQL databases?",
      "answer": "Tools are not as mature as relational databases\nLimited querying capabilities\nTraditional database capabilities not offered\nDifficulty of creating unique key data increases as amount of data increases\nDoes not work well with a lot interconnected relationships\nHigh learning curve for new developers\nNot many open-source options for enterprises\nNo standard guidelines for development",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 156,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as nature?",
      "answer": "Nature: MySql is relational and NoSQL is non-relational",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 157,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as design?",
      "answer": "MySql is table-based and NoSQL is document-based",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 158,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as scalability?",
      "answer": "MySQL is tough to scale for big data and NoSQL is not",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 159,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as model?",
      "answer": "MySQL requires detailed database design and NoSQL does not",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 160,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as community?",
      "answer": "MySQL has large expert community and NoSQL community is smaller",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 161,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as standardization?",
      "answer": "MySQL has a standard language with guidelines and NoSQL lacks a standard query language",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 162,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as schema?",
      "answer": "MySQL schema is rigid and NoSQL is dynamic according to needs",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 163,
      "question": "How does MySQL compare to NoSQL as far as flexibility?",
      "answer": "MySQL design changes affect the greatly affect the database and become inflexibility; NoSQL design changes do not affect the database, making it very flexible",
      "topic": "Databases - Part 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 177,
      "question": "What is the Internet?",
      "answer": "It is a worldwide, computer network that interconnects hundreds of types of computing devices.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 178,
      "question": "What is a Protocol?",
      "answer": "Governing of internet communication between two or more remote entities.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 179,
      "question": "What Protocol is used when a user makes a URL request in a browser?",
      "answer": "Transmission Control Protocol (TCP).",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 180,
      "question": "What forms a Network?",
      "answer": "Ethernet cables, bridges, routers and switches.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 181,
      "question": "What are the core components responsible for packet transmission in a network?",
      "answer": "Switches, hubs and bridges.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 182,
      "question": "What is Packet Switching?",
      "answer": "Mode of data transmission in which a message is broken into a number of parts sent independently, over whatever route is optimum for each packet, and reassembled at the destination.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 183,
      "question": "What is a Gateway?",
      "answer": "Networking hardware used in telecommunication networks that allows data to flow from one discrete network to another.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 184,
      "question": "What is Circuit Switching?",
      "answer": "Telecommunications network in which two network nodes establish a dedicated communications channel (circuit) through the network before the nodes may communicate.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 185,
      "question": "How is Circuit Switching different from Packet Switching?",
      "answer": "In Circuit Switching, the entire message is sent at once, and the entire link is reserved for communication.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 186,
      "question": "What are the 7 layers of the OSI (Open Systems Interconnection) Model?",
      "answer": "The Application, Presentation, Session, Transport, Network, Data Link and Physical Layer.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 187,
      "question": "What are the 3 Software Layers of the OSI (Open Systems Interconnection) Model?",
      "answer": "The Application, Presentation, and Session Layers.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 188,
      "question": "What are the 3 Hardware Layers of the OSI (Open Systems Interconnection) Model?",
      "answer": "The Network, Data Link and Physical Layers.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 189,
      "question": "What is the Core Layer of the OSI (Open Systems Interconnection) Model?",
      "answer": "The Transport Layer.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 190,
      "question": "What are the 5 layers of Computer Networks / Internet Technology?",
      "answer": "The Application, Transport, Internet, Network Interface and Physical Layers.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 191,
      "question": "What is the Client-Server Architecture?",
      "answer": "Architecture of a computer network in which many clients (remote processors) request and receive service from a centralized server (host computer) at fixed IP address. Client computers provide an interface to allow a computer user to request services of the server and to display the results the server returns.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 192,
      "question": "What is P2P Architecture?",
      "answer": "Peer-to-peer architecture is a commonly used computer networking architecture in which each workstation, or node, has the same capabilities and responsibilities (distributed workload).",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 1"
    },
    {
      "id": 193,
      "question": "What is the ideal of computations as a programmer?",
      "answer": "To express computations correctly, efficeintly and simply.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 194,
      "question": "What is the Divide and Conquer Strategy?",
      "answer": "Breaking up large and complex computations into smaller and simpler ones.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 195,
      "question": "What are the benefits of using functions to separate a given computation from the rest of a program?",
      "answer": "- makes computation logically separate\n- makes program text clearer by naming computation\n- makes it possible to use / call computation in other places in program\n- eases testing and debugging",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 196,
      "question": "What are Arguments within a function?",
      "answer": "The value(s) required by a function; a function's input(s).",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 197,
      "question": "What is the Input and Output of a function?",
      "answer": "The argument(s) and return value.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 198,
      "question": "What is the Block of a function?",
      "answer": "The body of a function; the lis tof statements that do the work.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 199,
      "question": "Are Return values within a function required?",
      "answer": "No, but the argument(s) are.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 200,
      "question": "What are Primitive Data Types?",
      "answer": "Basic building blocks provided by Python and other languages.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 201,
      "question": "What are Data Structures?",
      "answer": "Complex data structures, often including built-in functions, or methods, for performing various operations on data contained within them.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 202,
      "question": "What is a List.",
      "answer": "In Python, it is a numbered sequence of elements.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 203,
      "question": "What are Methods?",
      "answer": "Functions that are built in to an object.",
      "topic": "Computation - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 204,
      "question": "What is HTTP?",
      "answer": "Hyper Text Transfer Protocol; defines structure of and how messages are exchanged.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 205,
      "question": "What is HTTPS?",
      "answer": "Hyper Text Transfer Protocol Secure; HTTP with an added security layer (SSL).",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 206,
      "question": "What are the components of a HTTP Request?",
      "answer": "The Verb / Method, URI / Path, Version, and Request Header and Message.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 207,
      "question": "What are the components of a HTTP Response?",
      "answer": "The Response Code / Status Code and Message, HTTP Version, and Reponse Header and Message.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 208,
      "question": "What are the 4 Methods of HTTP?",
      "answer": "GET, POST, PUT and DELETE.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 209,
      "question": "What is the GET method of HTTP?",
      "answer": "Method used to retried information provided by server--no effect on data.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 210,
      "question": "What is the POST method of HTTP?",
      "answer": "Method used to send information (request) to server; example is login forms.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 211,
      "question": "What is the PUT method of HTTP?",
      "answer": "Method used to update content of the source with current content.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 212,
      "question": "What is the DELETE method of HTTP?",
      "answer": "Method used to remove the content of source.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 213,
      "question": "What is FTP?",
      "answer": "File Transfer Protocol; transfer with either local file system or remote host.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 214,
      "question": "What are the steps of FTP?",
      "answer": "1. Client initiates TCP connection with remote host (default PORT 21)\n2. Control connection\n3. Data connection\n4. File transfer (multiple file transfers multiple data connections)",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 215,
      "question": "What is SMTP?",
      "answer": "Simple Mail Transfer Protocol; transfers message from sender's mail server to recipient's mail server.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 216,
      "question": "What are the steps of SMTP?",
      "answer": "1. Sender sends message via user agent to sender's mail server\n2. TCP connection established with receiver's mail server (includes hand shake)\n3. Message is transmitted to receiver's mail server\n4. Either POP / IMAP is used to read mail",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 217,
      "question": "What does POP and IMAP stand for?",
      "answer": "Post Office Protocol and Internet Message Access Protocol",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 218,
      "question": "What is the DNS?",
      "answer": "Domain Name System; method of mapping website URLs to IP addresses.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 219,
      "question": "What are the 3 types of DNS servers?",
      "answer": "Root DNS, Top-level Domain and Authoritative DNS.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 220,
      "question": "What are the steps of a Basic DNS?",
      "answer": "1. Request information\n2. Ask the recursive DNS servers (aka DNS resolver)\n3. Ask the root name servers\n4. Ask the TLD name servers\n5. Ask the the Authoritative DNS servers\n6. Retrieve the record\n7. Receive the answer and cache",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 221,
      "question": "What is the Transport Layer?",
      "answer": "Layer that provides logical communication between application processes running on different hosts; accepts data (segments) from application layer and forwards to network.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 222,
      "question": "What are the two Transport Layer Protocols for the application layer?",
      "answer": "TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) and UDP (User Datagram Protocol)",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 223,
      "question": "What 4 controls are used by the Transport Layer to provide reliable data transfer?",
      "answer": "- Error control\n- Sequence control: ensures arrival of packets are sequenced for reassembly\n- Loss control: uses sequence numbers to ensure replacement of missing packets \n- Duplication control: discards duplicate segments received",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 224,
      "question": "What are the two major components of Process Communication?",
      "answer": "The sending process, aka the client process, that sends the message to another system in the form of a request; The receiving process, aka server process, that receives the message and possibly responds with message back.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 225,
      "question": "What step takes place in a TCP connection prior to data transfer?",
      "answer": "The client and server process first establish a connection, called the Hand Shake Protocol, and then data is transferred via TCP sockets.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 226,
      "question": "Why is a UDP considered an unreliable data transfer method?",
      "answer": "It is a connection-less model: a handshake does not occur prior to data transfer.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 227,
      "question": "What is Multiplexing and Demultiplexing?",
      "answer": "Multiplexing is the gathering of chunks of data from different sockets by transport layer into segments with header data for one network layer; Demultiplexing is the opposite.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 228,
      "question": "What is Routing?",
      "answer": "The path that a packet takes from its source to destination.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 229,
      "question": "What are Routing Algorithms?",
      "answer": "Algorithms used to calculate source to destination paths for packets.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 230,
      "question": "What is Forward Routing?",
      "answer": "The movement of a packet from a router's input link to the appropriate output link.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 2"
    },
    {
      "id": 231,
      "question": "What is an Algorithm?",
      "answer": "A step-by-step list of instructions for solving a problem.",
      "topic": "Flowcharts and Pseudocode"
    },
    {
      "id": 232,
      "question": "What are the charecteristics of an algorithm?",
      "answer": "- a finite number of well-defined instructions that can be effectively performed by a computing agent\n- a decription of a process that will halt after solving the problem\n- it solves a general class of problems",
      "topic": "Flowcharts and Pseudocode"
    },
    {
      "id": 233,
      "question": "What are the components of programming flowchart?",
      "answer": "- Terminal: (oval) start / stop of algorithm\n- Input / Output: (parallelogram) input or output\n- Process: (rectangle) processing operation\n- Decision: (diamond) a decision based on a question with more than one exit\n- Preparation: (hexagon) the initialization of variables\n- Connector: (circle) joins two or more flows",
      "topic": "Flowcharts and Pseudocode"
    },
    {
      "id": 234,
      "question": "What is Pseudocode?",
      "answer": "Informal method of writing algorithm instructions; useful for representing algorithms that are too long or complex to represent as flowcharts.",
      "topic": "Flowcharts and Pseudocode"
    },
    {
      "id": 235,
      "question": "What are examples of selective logic in pseudocode?",
      "answer": "IF, ENDIF, ELSEIF and ELSE",
      "topic": "Flowcharts and Pseudocode"
    },
    {
      "id": 236,
      "question": "What are examples of loops in pseudocode?",
      "answer": "DO, DOWHILE, and ENDDO",
      "topic": "Flowcharts and Pseudocode"
    },
    {
      "id": 237,
      "question": "What is the Network Service Model?",
      "answer": "Model that defines the end-to-end delivery of packets from source to destination.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 238,
      "question": "What are the possible services that the Network Layer provides?",
      "answer": "- Guranteed delivery\n- Guranteed delivery with bounded delay\n- Ordered packet delivery",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 239,
      "question": "What are the 3 components of the High Level View of Router Architecture?",
      "answer": "- Input ports: performs physical layer function of terminating input connection to router; perfroms link layer function of interoperatability with link on other side of router\n- Switching fabric: conenction between router input and output port\n- Output ports: stores packet received from switching fabric and transmits them to outgoing link",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 240,
      "question": "What are the 4 Routing Algorithms?",
      "answer": "- Static routing: routes change very slowly over time--human edits routing table\n- Dynamic routing: routing path is dynamic as network traffic or topology changes\n- Global routing: computes cheapest path between source and destination using complete network knowledge\n- Decentralized routing: computes cheapest path in interative or distributed manner",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 241,
      "question": "What is an IP Address?",
      "answer": "Address used to indentify device on network consisting of 2 parts--network and host address; host is device in network.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 242,
      "question": "What IPv4?",
      "answer": "- Internet Protocol version 4\n- Basis of the internet\n- Source and destination adress are 4 octet address--32 bits expressed in decimal belonging to host",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 243,
      "question": "What IPv6?",
      "answer": "- Internet Protocol version 6\n- 128 bits space for source / destination address\n- Does not require DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) or manual configuration",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 244,
      "question": "What is DHCP?",
      "answer": "- Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol\n- Uses UDP (User Datagram Protocol)\n- Allows server to automatically to assign IP address to host from defined range of numbers configured for network",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 245,
      "question": "What are the 4 steps of DHCP?",
      "answer": "1. DHCPDiscover: IP address request\n2. DHCPOffer: IP address offer\n3. DHCPRequest: IP address selection\n4. DHCPAck: IP adress acknowledgment",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 246,
      "question": "What are the services provided by the Link Layer?",
      "answer": "- Basic: moves datagram from one node to an adjacent node over a single communication link\n- Framing: encapsulates all datagrams from network layer into frames before link transmission\n- Link access: a MAC specifies rule by which a frame is transmitted over a link\n- Reliable delivery: ensures movement of network layer datagram through link without error",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 247,
      "question": "What is a MAC address?",
      "answer": "Media access control address; uniquely identifies device in a network.",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 248,
      "question": "How does a MAC address and IP address differ?",
      "answer": "- a MAC address uniquely identifies a device in a network\n- an IP address uniquely defines a network connection of a device\n- a MAC address is used to deliver data to the right device\n- an IP address is used to deliver data from one network to another\n ",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 249,
      "question": "What is ARP?",
      "answer": "- Address Resolution Protocol\n- Used by Internet Protocol to map IP network address to MAC physical address\n- Part of link layer and operates between network and link layers",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 250,
      "question": "What is RARP?",
      "answer": "- Reverse Address Resolution Protocol\n- Used to convert MAC ethernet address to IP address\n- Network admin creates table in LAN router mapping MAC address to IP address",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 251,
      "question": "What are the main types of cable?",
      "answer": "- Twisted pair cable (shielded and unshielded)\n- Coaxial cable\n- Fiber Optic",
      "topic": "Computer Networks - Part 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 252,
      "question": "What is Formal Logic?",
      "answer": "The foundation for organized method of thinking that characterizes reasoned activity; focused on the relationships of statements, as opposed to the content of a particular statement.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 253,
      "question": "What is the Study of Reasoning?",
      "answer": "Study of whether something is true or false.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 254,
      "question": "What are the applications of formal logic in computer science?",
      "answer": "- Circuit logic: logic governing computer circuitry\n- Conditions: allow programmers to make decisions based the state of environment (represented with variables)",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 255,
      "question": "What is a Statement?",
      "answer": "Also called a proposition; a sentence that is either true or false; truth value is either True (1) or False (0).",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 256,
      "question": "What are the Logical Connectives?",
      "answer": "- ˄ = conjunction (and)\n- ˅ = disjunction (or)\n- ~ = negation (not)\n- → = implication (if-then)",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 257,
      "question": "What is a Statement / Propositional Form?",
      "answer": "Expression consisting of statement variables and logical connectives; they become a statement when actual statements are substituted for the component statement variables; Example: (A˄~A) →  (B˄~C)",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 258,
      "question": "When is A ˄ B (A and B) true and when is it false?",
      "answer": "- True when both A and B are true\n- False when at least one of A or B is false",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 259,
      "question": "When is A ˅ B (A or B) true and when is it false?",
      "answer": "- True when at least one of A or B are true\n- False when both A and B is false",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 260,
      "question": "When is A → B (if A then B) true and when is it false?",
      "answer": "- True if A is false, regardless of truth of B\n- Flase when A is true and B is false; true otherwise",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 261,
      "question": "What is a Truth Table?",
      "answer": "A table that displays the truth values of a statement corresponding to the different combinations of possible truth values for variables.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 262,
      "question": "What is a WFF",
      "answer": "Well-formed formula; combination of letters, connectives and parentheses than generates a expression that is meaningful.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 263,
      "question": "What is the Order of Precedence?",
      "answer": "Order stipulated in which connectives can be applied:\n1. Connectives within innermost parentheses first and then progress outwards\n2. Negation (~)\n3. Conjunction (˄)\n4. Implication (→)\n5. Equivalence (↔)",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 264,
      "question": "What is a Tautology?",
      "answer": "A WFF that is intrisically true, regardless of the truth values of its statements; e.g. it will rain today or it will not rain today (A˅~A); usually represented by a 1.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 265,
      "question": "What is a Contradiction?",
      "answer": "A WFF that is intrisically false, regardless of the truth values of its statements; e.g. it will rain today and it will not rain today (A˄~A); usually represented by a 0.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 266,
      "question": "When are two statements forms called logically equivalent?",
      "answer": "If they have identical truth values for each possible substition of statements for their statement variables; represented by P⇔Q or P≡Q.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 267,
      "question": "What are the common Tautological Equivalences?",
      "answer": "Commutative, Associative, Distributive, Identity and Complement.",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    },
    {
      "id": 268,
      "question": "What are DeMorgan's Laws?",
      "answer": "- ~(A˅B) ≡ ~A˄~B\n- ~(A˄B) ≡ ~A˅~B",
      "topic": "Logic and Truth Tables"
    }
  ]
}
